const questions: Array<QuestionType> = [
  {
    question: 'ἀνήρ',
    explanation: '(androgeen)',
    answers: ['man', 'echtgenoot'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'ἀστήρ',
    explanation: '(astrologie, asterisk)',
    answers: ['ster'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'μάρτυς',
    answers: ['getuige'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'σωτήρ',
    answers: ['redder'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'χείρ',
    answers: ['hand'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'γυνή',
    explanation: '(gynaecoloog)',
    answers: ['vrouw', 'echtgenote'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'σάρξ',
    explanation: '(sarcofaag)',
    answers: ['vlees'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'ἐλπις',
    answers: ['hoop'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'νύξ',
    answers: ['nacht'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'παῖς',
    answers: ['jongen', 'meisje', 'kind', 'dienaar'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'πούς',
    explanation: '(podoloog)',
    answers: ['voet'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'χάρις',
    answers: ['genade'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'αἰών',
    explanation: '(aeon)',
    answers: ['eeuw', 'tijdperk'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'εἰς τὸν αἰῶνα',
    answers: ['voor altijd'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'εἰς τοὺς αἰῶνας τῶν αἰώνων',
    answers: ['tot het einde der tijden'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'ἀμπελών',
    answers: ['wijngaard'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'εἰκών',
    explanation: '(ikoon)',
    answers: ['beeld'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'Ἓλλην',
    explanation: '(hellenistisch)',
    answers: ['Griek'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'μήν',
    answers: ['maand'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'Σίμων',
    answers: ['Simon'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'ἄρχων',
    explanation: '(archont)',
    answers: ['leider'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'θυγάτηρ',
    answers: ['dochter'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'μήτηρ',
    answers: ['moeder'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'πατήρ',
    explanation: '(patrologie)',
    answers: ['vader'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  }
]
const lesson28Vocabulary: LessonType = {
  id: 'lesson28-vocabulary',
  name: 'Les 28 – Woordenschat',
  type: 'woordenschat',
  active: false,
  questions
}
export default lesson28Vocabulary
